Committing Adultery in Your Heart is…
Prev  |   |  Next

Committing Adultery in Your Heart is…

We did not stay late enough to see Eve return from her date. The next Monday, I arrived at school in time only to discover my first lesson was cancelled. So I went to the computer lab.

As I was pounding on the computer, I heard a “Hey Jenn!”. It was Eve. She was wearing some Jeans and a T-shirt with the Linux penguin and some inscriptions on. Her hair was flowing in all directions and she was wearing good makeup. She looked great.

“Hi Eve! So how was your date?”

“Heh, Jenn, I’m gonna get you for this… one day… I swear.”

“What’s wrong?”

“Well, Taylor could not help staring at me the whole time. When we got to the cinema and the movie started he actually hugged me with his arms.”

“Using the stretching trick?”

“No.”

“So what did you do?”

“I sort of cuddled into him. Then he smelled my hair. So I asked him ‘How did it smell?’ and he said ‘It smells lovely.’. Is he British?”

“No, he’s not.” I said.

“That wasn’t the worst part. After the movie was over, he told me that I was too good for a Pizza, and instead took me to Loro’s.”

“Loro’s a very nice restaurant. Not too expensive but very nice.”

“I know!”, she exclaimed, “and we were chatting all this time. And when the meal ended, he insisted on paying for my part of the dinner. You know I have my financial resources.”

“Yes, I do.”

“Then he escorted me home, and when we arrived there, he asked if I want a good night kiss. I said ‘OK’, and we kissed. Well, it turned out to be more than a kiss - we were totally making out.”

“And…”, I said eagerly.

“I stopped him, said ‘Good night, bye, see you at school.’ and went inside. Didn’t want to push it too far.”

“So you’re not going to see him again?” I asked her, puzzled.

“Are you kidding? That was my best date of all time. I’d better set up another one.”

“Nice, ” I said. “It’s really nice seeing you two together.”

“OK,” she said, “I’ll better get going. Oh wait… can you come with me, two days from now, and help me shop for new clothes and for things to decorate my room with?”

“Sure,” I said, “why not?”

“Great! And do you mind if I join you and Taylor in your gym workout? ‘Sound mind in a sound body’?”

“No problem here. And I think Taylor would love to see you more often.”

“Judging by yesterday, I think he actually may. Ta ta!”

“Bye!”.

Taylor entered the same room after about 20 minutes. “Hi!” I told him, “How was your date last Friday?”

“It went pretty well.”

“That’s it?”

“I guess…” he said hesitantly.

I was shocked. “Man, you guys make awful gossipers.”

“Oh… Eve was here, wasn’t she? And she told you all about it.”

“Yep. You smelled her hair and said it smelled lovely. You bought her dinner at a rather fancy restaurant.”

“Yes, it was a wonderful date, I guess. Eve was so great the other night.”

“Yeah, she was.”

“Thanks for… you know… transforming her and all.”

“You’re welcome.”

When Eve and I got together to go shopping, we went to a clothes shop. “You know, my newfound powers are intoxicating. Three guys hit on me at school since the weekend, including this really cute Football player.” she said.

“Hmmm… ” I said.

“Are you ladies alright?” the shop’s clerk (Tim, a young and handsome man) approached us.

“Hey Tim!” I said, “I don’t believe you know my friend Eve here.”

“Eve Siegel!” she said and extended her hand.

“Tim O’Brian.” he said and they shook hands. “OK, I’ll be there if you need me…”

Eve followed him with her gaze for a few seconds, and then smiled and went back to looking at the clothes.

“Will you stop that?” I whispered to her.

“Stop what?” she said.

“You’re totally into him.”

“So I’m lusting him a little bit, so what? ‘But I say unto you, that whosoever looketh on a woman to lust after her, hath committed adultery with her already in his heart.’”

“Well, girlfriend, committing adultery in your heart is perfectly harmless and quite rewarding. And I’m not really raping anyone. I’m tenderly making love to them.”

“Listen,” I snapped at her, “Taylor is my best friend, and I swear that if you…”

“I’m crazy about Taylor.” she interrupted me.

“What?” I said.

She changed her pose. “I’m crazy about Taylor. Always have been. I promise I wouldn’t do anything to hurt him.”

“You always have been crazy about Taylor? Why didn’t you tell him that?”

“Come on, have you looked at me then? I wasn’t his type. He always dated these well-groomed girls, who had some sense not to rebel like I did. Hell, he also dated this incredibly dumb cheerleader once.”

“Stacie wasn’t dumb!”

“I was being sarcastic! My point is that he was way out of my league.”

“Oh!” I said and tried to hug her.

“No hug!” she said. “In any case, I’ll do my best to make things work between Taylor and I. And even if they don’t, we’ll remain good friends. The kind of friends who go to movies together, or socialise at LUG meetings, fix dates for each other, etc.”

“Good, I’m glad to hear that. Now where were we?”

“Picking clothes.” she said, and after a while added: “You know, we should drop by Radio Shack and get some dolls of Tux and Beastie the BSD Daemon. I totally dig these guys. Oh! And a nice Looney Toons poster. I’d hate to pump money into the MPAA’s lawsuit machine, but I really like Marvin the Martian.”

“Who are you, and what have you done to Erisa?”

“Hey, the makeover was your idea, Jennifer. What have you done to Erisa?” and we both laughed.

Prev  |   |  Next
“Divine”’s Good  | Home |  Man, it was so exciting!

I’m just a Geek…
Prev  |   |  Next

I’m just a Geek…

“I hate her, I positively and completely hate her.” I said to Jonathan. (Who, like I said, was my boyfriend)

We were sitting in a nice restaurant having dinner. Yet, I could think of nothing more pleasant to bring than Erisa and her idiosyncrasies.

“Jenn, Taylor seems to be fond of her, so she cannot be all bad. Maybe she just sees you as a stereotype.”

“Well,” I told him, “I’m not going to stop liking Atomic Kitten, just because she thinks they are a girly band. And I am a girl, damn it!”

“I have a better idea: why don’t you prove to her that you’re competent as a programmer? She seems to like Taylor, even though we both know that he likes Atomic Kitten and all the other girly bands as much as you.”

“Well, maybe you’re right. I still have time on this weekend, I could try learning HTML and getting most of my homepage done. I think the next week won’t be so busy and so I can tweak it even more.”

“Right, maybe that way you’ll earn her respect.”

And so I did. I studied HTML (Hyper Text Markup Language) and its CSS (Cascading Style Sheets) thing. I created a homepage with:

Some information about myself. My bio, my C.V.

Pictures of myself and my family.

Some jokes and quotations I was fond of.

Links to books that I liked.

Links to my friends’ web-pages.

Some rants and raves about movies I’ve been to.

Some pages about the Power Puff Girls, Atomic Kitten and Britney Spears. (I added them to tease Erisa)

All of this with a nice style — I played with the colours endlessly to get them right — and everything. It was actually quite fun, and I found myself doing it when I got too tired of doing homework.

Eventually, I had a lot to show for. When Saturday came, I showed it to Erisa.

“Not bad.” she said, “Not bad at all. Good content, nice style; nice , portable markup. You have validated everything right?”

“Yes.”

“Good. Now let’s upload it. I happen to have my own private place on the Internet, for which I’m paying good money. I’ll give you an account there, if you promise not to abuse it. Wait a sec! Thinking about it, there’s no way someone like you will know how to abuse it.”

“Hmmpppfff…” I said.

“In any case, let me sit in front of the computer for a second.”

We switched places, she opened up this weird window full of monospaced text, typed a few obscure commands, and after about 10 minutes, she said: “here you go. Your username is ‘jennray’ and your password is the same as one on this computer. Now, I’ll write a script that will upload it to the server, if you just type the password. Meanwhile, just take it for granted. Later on, I’ll explain what it does, but we still have a lot of ground to cover beforehand.”

I was beginning to like her.

“Another thing - our Linux User Group (or LUG for short) gathers around every first and third Wednesday of the month at 17:00 at the local university. You should come and get to know Linux better by listening to the presentations that people give there.”

Wow! These Linux guys have nothing to do twice a month, than attend a presentation about it. But, then I thought about graduating from somewhere nice like Harvard or Berkeley and I said, “OK, I’ll come.”

“Heh, the other girls there are more similar to you than to me.”

“Man, I am relieved.”

“You should be, girlfriend!”

“My name’s Jennifer.”

“Listen, Blondie, I couldn’t care less about you or the whole culture and values you represent. I’m just a geek who is trying to make the world a better place. What have you done for the world recently?”

“Heh”, I snapped at her, “at least I care about myself enough to dress properly, and to look my best, and to care about other people. You, on the other hand, make me miserable, so I would not call it making the world a better place.”

“Tough luck, Blondie. Your feelings are not facts, and you cannot sue me for making you miserable. I have plenty of friends whom I seem to bring a lot of joy to.”

“Who, like your boyfriend?”

“I don’t have a boyfriend and haven’t had one for a long time. I’m still dating guys, though.”

“Do they call you back?”

“Not usually, and that’s because I ask them not to.”

“You’re pathetic.”

“At least I don’t need your help in learning how to hack.”

“Which reminds me,” she added, “if you want to get your money’s worth, you’d better want us to continue the lesson, instead of ping-ponging accusations between ourselves. Shall we go on?”

I stopped liking her after this twist of the conversation.

Prev  |   |  Next
Are You Done Insulting Me?  | Home |  Hardware Hackers are…

RMS is Coming to Town
Prev  |   |  Next

RMS is Coming to Town

One day, when Jonathan, Taylor, and I were having a conversation in one of our school hallways, we saw Eve approaching us, carrying a piece of paper, and looking very anxious to see us.

“Hi Eve, what’s up?” Jonathan said.

“Hey guys - I have very exciting news: ”, she said as she approached us and then kissed Taylor briefly. “RMS is coming to town!”, and she let us see her sheet.

In case you don’t know, “RMS” is Richard M. Stallman. He was one of the original hackers in the MIT Artificial Intelligence Laboratory. He also coined the term “Free Software” (“Free” as in “Free Speech” or “Freedom”) which describes a certain licensing model of software programs and components, that is now popular among individual developers, many large and small corporations and many other organisations. This model later also became known as “open source software”, which is now likely the most popular term for that, and the one that my friends and I are using usually, especially when speaking with laymen. (Some software activists still feel there is a semantic and ideological difference between the terms “free software” and “open source”, but I’m not too infatuated with that distinction.)

In any case, Stallman then went on to create the GNU project, as part of which a great deal of free software packages (or “open source” ones if you may), which make up a large and integral part of many modern-day UNIX-like systems (and are even available and commonly used on some non-open-source UNIX systems and some not-so-UNIX-like systems such as Microsoft Windows). The GNU-based UNIXes include the systems now known as “Linux” systems, which run the Linux operating system kernel combined with the GNU run-time and other free software user-land components (and as such, Stallman and other GNU people insist on calling them “GNU/Linux” instead).

“Great!” Taylor said looking at the paper. “Jenn, would you like to meet him?”

“I suppose.” I said, “I’d rather not miss on this opportunity. Albeit he does have a reputation for being very stubborn. How is he in real-life?”

“Well, Taylor and I met him last time he’s been here.” Eve said, “We also signed each other’s keys. He’s very nice in real-life: intelligent, funny, and a very nice hippy-like person. I’m sure you’ll like him.”

“Well, there’s a key-signing party there too. Hmmm… it’s a bit far from here. I think the four of us should borrow a car. Jonathan, are you coming, too?”

“Sure, why not? What’s a key-signing party?”

Eve replied: “A key-signing is something you do with your cryptographical public-key and private key pair. You sign a person’s key and thus acknowledge you have verified that the key belongs to this actual person.”

“Key-signing parties are fun, but if you ask me, the chance of someone performing a man-in-the-middle attack over the Internet is god-damn small. Heck, I bet even the NSA cannot do that.”

“Hmmm… ” I said, “I don’t have a GPG [= GNU Privacy Guard] key-pair yet. I guess I’ll generate one for the occasion. Is there a howto document or something like this?”

“Yep,” Taylor said, “the Key-Signing Party Howto. Using GPG is not exactly rocket science.”

“Cool!” I said. And then we discussed the arrangements for picking everyone up.

The day of the meeting, I placed everything I needed in a backpack, and went to Taylor’s house for the ride. Eve was already there and we waited for Jonathan, who arrived shortly afterwards. So, we all entered the car, and drove there.

The hallroom in which Stallman’s presentation and get-together took place was quite crowded, which was expected. We spotted Mr. Stallman there, but decided to approach him only at the general get-together afterwards.

RMS gave a very entertaining presentation about the history of the free software movement, what it meant to him, and how we can help. He told the shop-worn story of his life at the MIT Artificial Intelligence Lab, the incident with the printer, and what he has done to remedy the situation. He also gave the standard preaching about why it was important to say “Free Software” instead of “Open-Source” and “GNU/Linux” instead of just “Linux”. Throughout the talk, he told a great deal of jokes, which caused the audience to burst into laughter. It was great.

Then he gave some time for questions from the audience. They were also answered assertively and sometimes funnily. Then the key-signing party took place.

We decided that Stallman will sign keys with each and every local separately and then the locals can sign each other’s keys. I stood in a long line, showed Mr. Stallman some pictorial IDs and vice versa. Eve and Taylor did not take part in it, because they had already signed his key. Instead they spent some time talking between themselves. Eventually, RMS was free, and we continued the key-signing between ourselves. Then came time for some socialising: Dr. Stallman brought some books and other gifts which he intended to sell to gather money for the Free Software Foundation (while autographing them).

After a while, Eve approached him. “Hi Mr. Stallman!” she said, “I’m Eve Siegel. I’ve seen you in L.A. a couple of years ago. You may remember me as Erisa. We talked on E-mail later on - about the evils of big business, free software ideology and stuff like that.”

“‘Erisa’, yes, I remember you. Didn’t you have… ahmmm… green hair back then?”

“Yes, as a matter of fact. Since then it became purple, but now I’m au natural.”

“You look nice.” Stallman said.

“Thanks. You too. So what are you doing now?”

“Oh the usual, advocating free software, trying to convert the world to the free software ideology.”

“Good, someone ought to do it. Are you seeing anyone by any chance?”

“No. I’m not seeing anyone at the moment”.

“Oh well. In any case, please meet my friend and protégé for hacking - Jennifer Raymond. Jennifer, Mr. Stallman and vice versa.”.

“Nice to meet you, Mr. Stallman.” I said. “I’ve heard so much about you.”

“Well, everything positive you’ve heard about me is true, but also some of the negative things.”

Eve and I laughed, and RMS quickly joined us. But then some other attendee wanted to talk to Stallman, and we let them converse.

We arrived at Taylor’s house, and Eve and I walked home together from there. On the way, I said to Eve, “There’s something I don’t get.”

“What?”

“RMS is like this really funny and intelligent guy, and he’s a really cute hippy, and he had his share of life achievements and stuff…”

“Right.”

“And he’s in his fifties now, and you know that girls dig older man. So how come when you asked him if he’s seeing anyone, he said he doesn’t? Why does he have a problem finding a suitable life-partner?”

“Oh, Jennifer, Jennifer… you are so naïve. Why don’t I drop by your house and show you some stuff he wrote on his homepage.” Eve replied.

“OK.”, I said puzzled.

Richard Stallman’s homepage greeted the random web-surfer with some political action items. It was hardly a pleasant way to be introduced to a web-page, and not my idea of a page I’d like to visit often. Then Eve showed me his former personal ad. It reads, and I quote:

I’m a single atheist white man, 50, reputedly intelligent, with unusual interests in politics, science, music and dance.

I’d like to meet a woman with varied interests, curious about the world, comfortable expressing her likes and dislikes (I hate struggling to guess), delighting in her ability to fascinate a man and in being loved tenderly, who values joy, truth, beauty and justice more than “success”--so we can share bouts of intense, passionately kind awareness of each other, alternating with tolerant warmth while we’re absorbed in other aspects of life.

My 19-year-old child, the Free Software Movement, occupies most of my life, leaving no room for more children, but I still have room to love a sweetheart. I spend a lot of my time traveling to give speeches, often to Europe, Asia and Latin America; it would be nice if you were free to travel with me some of the time.

“Oh, my God!” I said after I read it.

“Do you wonder why now?”

“Not any more. Any half-normal girl would be scared off by the message he’s trying to give.”

“Yeah, I always thought so too.” Eve noted.

“But I might put him in the list of the 5 celebrities I’m allowed to have sex with.” I said.

Eve replied: “Hmmm… cool! He’s incredibly sexy. But I can warn you that I don’t think he’s much of a casual sex guy. You can always ask him that on E-mail.”

Prev  |   |  Next
“Abandoning” Debian  | Home |  “Who will Take a Second Look at it, unless…”

“She still is…”
Prev  |   |  Next

“She still is…”

Erisa continued to tutor me, and I continued to learn new things. Perl is positively huge and has many nuances. Eventually, Erisa told me that I was good enough to start contributing to open-source projects. She recommended looking for interesting CPAN (= Comprehensive Perl Archive Network) modules, adding automated tests, doing bug-squashing, and maybe even adding a feature or two.

That’s what I did, and found myself contributing to various modules. Then, one day, Erisa approached me as I was taking things out of my locker. “Jenn,” she said, “I told my Mum about you, and now she bugs me about inviting you to dinner at my place. Would you like to come?”

“Sure! I’d love to come.” I told her.

“Good, it will give you a chance to see my computer and I’ll show you what a working environment of real men and real women is. Not the sissy environment that I recommended you to start with.”

“Heh.” I said and smiled.

We scheduled for the next day at 19:00. So, the next day, I wore some of my best clothes, and prepared myself for two hours. As I looked on my final form in the mirror, I said to myself, that I probably would have looked better than Erisa with much less effort. And so I walked to Erisa’s home.

She answered the door. Looking at her, I noticed I was right - she did look awful. “Hey Jenn,” she said, “please come in.”.

“Now I can warn you that my family likes to call me ‘Eve’. I don’t mind it too much, but to avoid bad habits, you should refer to me as ‘Erisa’.”

“OK. Why did you change your name in the first place?”

“Well, every person should have a right to choose his own name. My parents called me ‘Eve’ because they wanted a nice Hebrew name. I, on the other hand, am trying to be unique and individualistic, so I renamed myself.”

“I’m never going to change my name. I like it a lot.”

“Girlfriend, it’s you who succumbs to society, not me.”

Then I noticed a young boy (dressed perfectly normally) descending down the stairs. He looked at me, and said, “Eve, is this Jennifer?”.

“Righto.” Erisa said.

I approached him and said “Jennifer Raymond! Nice to meet you. Are you Erisa’s brother?”.

“Yeah,” he answered, “my name is Daniel Siegel.”

“Nice to meet you, Daniel.”

“Nice to meet you, too, Miss Raymond.”

“Hey, you can call me Jennifer.”

He looked a bit puzzled, and after a few seconds said “Whatever.” and ran to a different room.

“Well, as a good hostess, let me tell you what there’s to do here.” Erisa addressed me. “In the living room we have video games, a DVD player, and a VHS player. My family has bought a large selection of movies and video games. I have, for a long time, frowned upon this practice, as it pumps money into the content industry’s lawsuit machine. Nevertheless, I still don’t mind using them once they are purchased.”

“My personal computer is in my room up-stairs.” she added, “There are a few things I’d like to show you there.”

“I’d love to see your room. And to meet your parents.” I told her.

“Well, let’s go to my room now, OK? And then we can find some other entertainment for you until the food is ready.”

And so I followed her up the stairs. Erisa’s room reflected upon her personality. While the walls were white (luckily), it was filled with posters of Heavy Metal bands, with activism posters, and with a large amount of books (some of them had Hebrew writing on the cover). It exhibited a lot of disorder. In one corner, stood a desk with a nice PC computer beneath it, a flat screen on top, and a keyboard.

Erisa took the seat next to the screen and hinted that I should take the seat next to her.

“See, this is Debian - a distribution that real men and real women (trademark) use. It is maintained by a group of packagers worldwide, is controlled by an organization, instead of one of those companies that don’t really care about their users.”

“The first thing you should notice is that I login with a text mode. Newbies dig an X-login, but it causes many problems. After you are in a virtual console, you can start X-Windows [= the Linux windowing system] using ‘startx’.”

“And here’s IceWM - a usable window manager that actually does not eat your computer’s resources like KDE or GNOME do. Other people use fluxbox or whatever, but Ice works for me.”

“Cool,” I said. “I suppose I can give it a try. It does not seem to have as much eye candy as KDE does.”

“Eye candy in - memory and speed out.”

“Heeee.” I giggled. “Anything else you want to show me?”

“Well, can’t think of anything now. Why don’t you go downstairs and meet my family? The food should be ready soon.”

I went downstairs. Daniel was watching a film I really liked so I joined him. Eventually, Erisa’s mother called everybody to say that the food was ready.

Erisa’s family talked a lot during the meal, and I joined them whenever I could. I noticed that they called Erisa “Eve” (as she had previously noted). The food was delicious.

After the meal, Erisa’s father and her older brother had volunteered to clear the table, and her mother asked me if I’d like to look at Erisa’s photo albums. “I’d love to.” I said.

As a girl, Erisa was super-cute. “Us being Jews, she grew among lots of Jewish and Israeli kids, and she learned Hebrew very quickly. She also eventually learned how to read it, even without diacritics. Some of our Israeli friends and relatives were amazed at her mastery of the language, and said her accent hardly revealed her true birthplace.”

“She was so proud of her Jewish heritage and culture. Here are some pictures of her during her Bat-Mitzvah.”

I looked at them with interest. “So when did she become such a…”

“Punk?” Erisa interrupted me, “That’s alright - I fully acknowledge this fact.”

“Well, ” said her mother, “around the age of 14. She started staying away from her usual friends, dressing weirdly, and colouring her hair in flashy colours. We don’t believe in dictating our children how to lead their life, so we just let her be.”

“Was it because of her interest in computers?”

“Oh no,” she said, “she’s been tampering with computers since she was a little girl. She used to invite her friends, both girls and boys, home and show them how to play games and program. It was all very social. We don’t know what happened. She was always so caring for other people.”

“She still is…” I said.

Erisa smiled, and then went back to reading her book. After a short while, she said: “You know, I’m not exactly Miss Altruism here. As much as I think commercialisation is evil, and Big Business is aiming to ruin our country and the world at large, I still think tangible goods and especially people’s time is something that does not have to be given away.”

“Fair enough,” I replied, “I can agree with that. So?”

“Well, just for your information, by charging people for my time alone, I now have over 20 thousand bucks in the bank.”

“You’re kidding?” I asked surprisingly.

“She isn’t.” Erisa’s mother replied.

“How did you earn all of that?”

“Well, Mum and Dad finance my food, my clothing, and school, so I don’t have to worry about that. I used to work during the Summers for software shops, and I also give lessons (as is the case with you), work as a freelancer and have other gigs.”

“I’ll give you an extreme example: one day, in the very beginning of the Internet craze, this old man sent a mail to a mailing list I was a member of, asking for help trying to form a web-site of his own (with pictures of his grand-children, and stuff like that). I told him, that it won’t be scalable to create and maintain the site for him, and that he should learn HTML. It turned out he was living in the other side of L.A., so I said that I will be willing to teach him that, if he pays me for my entire time, including the long rides.”

“So he agreed and I actually taught him. Took a long time. You know, people his age can sometimes type very slowly, and he was not exceptional. After that, when he learned HTML, I told him that I’ll be willing to host his site on my server for a uniform monthly fee. He agreed.”

“So I got a lot of money teaching him, and now I get a constant stream of cash from him. He and his wife actually now totally dig having a web-site, and they fill it in with reviews and recommendations of their favourite movies, recipes, bio’s, memorial pages, and stuff like that.”

I shed a few tears and wiped them with my elbow. “Erisa,” I told her, “that is one of the sweetest stories I’ve ever heard. You must be the most compassionate girl in the world, and…”

“‘Compassionate’ my ass!”, Erisa interrupted me, “I’m charging this poor old man, instead of just hosting him on my server, free of charge.”

“I still think it’s very sweet of you.”

“Well, Blondie, sweet or not, my time and my resources are not distributed freely. It’s a tough world, and if you want to make it a better place, you should not give away your time, because it’s too precious to be worthless.”

“‘Blondie’, again?”

Erisa grinned. “Jennifer, the only reason I call you ‘Blondie’ is because I’m a sweet and compassionate girl who totally digs your hair colour.”

I reached to hug her. “No hug!” she snapped at me, as I stopped, and retreated, while she returned to her book.

Prev  |   |  Next
BETH!  | Home |  MIME, POE, XUL and other Beasts